Come on, Alejandro, it is my turn. Let's me see.
快点 阿利亚多 该我了 让我看看
Montero!
蒙特罗
Freedom! Freedom! Freedom!
往后 往后 往后 自由 自由 自由
What are you doing cutting holes in my wagon?
嗨”你们在我的马车上搞什么鬼
lam sorry, Senor Lopez.
对不起 洛佩兹先生
We were just waiting for Zorro.
我们在等着看佐罗
Go home, muchachos.
回家去吧 “小家伙
Do you think he's really going to come, Senor Lopez?
你认为他真的会来吗 洛佩汞先生
Someone thinks he will.
有人认为他会来
Joaquin, Alejandro...
沃金 阿利亚多
once I carved coffins for your mother and father.
你们父母的棺材都是我做的
[ would hate to carve ones for you.
我可不想再给你们做
Now go!
快回去吧
Alejandro, Joaquin...
阿利亚多 沃金
this is no place for you.
你们不该来这
Now, get back to the mission.
赶快回教堂去
Don Montero, for the love of God, why are you still here?
蒙特罗先生 看在上帝的份上 你怎么还没有走
Now, now, Don Luiz. Calm, calm.
不要大惊小怪 镇静 镇静
Santa Anna's men are three miles from the town.
山塔安纳的人离城只有三英里了
You have to go sir. Now!
你必须马上离开这里
The, government of Spain
对于你的尽忠职守
would like to thank you for your devoted service.
西班牙政府会感谢你的
This land is the property of the Spanish government.
这块土地属于西班牙政府所有
And, in two hours' time,
两个小时之内
it will be the property of the Mexican government,
就要回墨西哥政府了
unless I hand them over to you.
除非我把她交给你
I'm well acquainted with Santa Anna.
我了解山塔安纳
He will realize that the dons will be dutiful taxpayers,
她知道贵族们都是 忠实的纳税者
and he will respect your claims.
他会尊重你的权力
The, rest of Alta California
我已经把加利福尼亚
I have divided up equally among the other dons.
其它的地方平均分给了别的贵族
trust that you will make sure that all of them receive their grants.
我相信你能够确保他们 得到自己的胜利
Get the children out... of the plaza immediately!
让所有的儿童马上离开广场
The children should never have to see the things we do.
我们的事 不应该让孩子们看到
I want to see!
你放我下来”我要看
Put me down!
放我下来 放我下来呀
Zorro?
佐罗
I saw him.
我看见他了
I saw Zorro.
我看见佐如了
Come here!
跟我来
Attencion!
注意了 立正
Who are these men
他们是什么人
that you would risk your life to have them killed?
值得你置生命危险杀掉他们
Who are they? I have no idea.
什么人”我也不知道
Three peasants pulled at random from the crowd.
是从人群中随便抓了三个农民
Where is he?
佐罗呢
Come on.
跟我来
My thanks to you gentlemen.
多谢了先生们
Now if you will excuse me...
好了 要是你们不介意的话
I'm missing my own party.
我要去找朋友们了
Kill him!
杀死他
Zorro!
佐罗
You would murder three innocent men just to capture me?
为了抓我 你要牺牲三条无幸的生命
I would murder a hundred innocent men
只要杀死你
if it meant killing you.
一百条人命我也在所不异
Three men, three cuts.
三个人”一人一下
Asmall memento of Mexico,
墨西哥留给你的纪念
Rafael...to remind you not to return.
永远不要再回来
Zorro! Zorro! Zo...
佐罗，”佐罗 佐罗
Tornado, my old friend...
我的老朋友
you're getting too old for this.
干这个你太老了
Yes, me too.
没错 ”我也是
But the good prince was not afraid of the evil king.
可是好王子一点也不怕坏国王
He raced across the drawbridge, fighting off a hundred guards.
他冲过了吊桥 和一百名卫兵展开了激战
And then, looking very handsome
然后在夕阳的辉映下
and dashing in the late afternoon sun,
以矫健的身姿
he leapt...onto the balcony and thrus this enchanted sword...
腾空跃上了阳台 用他那把无敌的宝剑
under the king's chin.
项住了国王的咽喉
"You would kill three innocent men,"
你不惜牺牲三条无的生命
he...demanded, "just to capture me?"
就为了抓我
"Yes. "
是的
Then suddenly, lightning flashed
突然 “”随着闪电
and a mighty thunder shocked the wasted land.
响起一声炸雷 令落范的大地为之震惊
And the evil king glared at the good prince...
坏国王死死盯住好王子
and said...
说了一名
something very forgettable.
令人难忘的话
And the good prince... what did he do?
那个好王子后来怎么样了
Well, he leapt from the balcony onto his faithful old steed, Tornado,
他从阳台飞身跃上 他那匹忠诚的战驹
and...raced home to his beautiful wife...
黑旋风”一溜烟的回到了娇妻
Esperanza... and to his little child, Elena...
爱佩莎…和爱女伊莲娜身边
never to do anything so foolish...
从此再也不敢匡撞了
or dangerous again.
很危险的事情
She loves to hear your stories.
她非常喜欢听你讲故事
Oh, it's...only the sound of my voice.
其实是我的声音吸引了她
One day she'll have no time for them.
总有一天她会对这些不感兴趣
I never tire of them. Why should she?
可我听不够”她也一样
Esperanza.
爱佩莎
She already has your strength.
你的力量已经传给她了
Today she broke the little clay horse you made for her...
今天她把你给她做的泥马 给捏碎了
Diego...
狄葛
It's just a scratch. It's all right.
只控破点皮 “没关系
-Diego, you promised me. -l know.
狄葛。 你向我保证过
No more nights waiting up, praying you'll come home alive.
不再让我独守空夜”担惊受怕的
The Spaniards are going home.
西班牙人就要滚蛋了
Today is Zorro's last ride.
今天是佐罗的最后行动
From now on we'll...
从今晚后
grow old together with our five children.
我们可以终身相伴 养五个孩子
Five?
五个
Yeah. Not enough?
对“还不够吗
I love you.
我爱你
Dona de la Vega...
德罗维加夫人
still as beautiful as ever.
你还是那么漂亮
Don Rafael.
拉斐尔先生
What an honor... the governor in my home.
我很荣幸 ”总督大人轰到
You will stay for dinner, of course.
我一定要留你吃顿饭
I have come to apologize, Esperan...za.
我是来向爱佩莎道歉的
I'm sorry that I could not protect this country
对不起”我没有能够阻止农民
from the peasants who have overrun it.
从我们手中夺取了这片土地
I'm sorry that I couldn't make you love me.
对不起 我没能赢得你的爱情
And I'm sorry that [ have to leave you without a husband.
对不起”我不得不让你守喜了
Arrest him.
还捕他
Blood never lies...
血迹不会撒谎
Zorro.
佐罗
You're a traitor to your country and your class.
你背叛了你的国家和阶级
Take him away.
带走
Wait!
等等
No!
不
[ would never have let any harm come to her.
我从来没想过要伤害她
She was never yours to protect.
她用不着你来保护
Elena.
伊莲娜
] want you to live...
我要你活着
with the knowledge that you have lost everything that you hold dear.
活着忍受失去了亲人的痛苦
] want you to suffer, as I have suffered,
我要你受前熬像我一样
knowing that your child should have been mine.
领着你的孩子却属于我
Elena!
伊莲娜
Let me hold her.
把她给我
Rafael!
拉斐尔
She has her mother's eyes.
她的眼睛像母亲
You'll never be rid of me!
你永远别想摆脱我
Rafael!
拉斐尔
Caught the bandits, plain to see doo da, doo da.
盗匪被我打得啼哩哗啦
big, tough and mean, but don't...scare me.
可我不怕你
Oh, doo da day.
狗东西
Stayed on their track bringin' em back.
有我出击 他们就完戏
So pay the bounty now to me because...
快把赏金装进我特里 因为.. .
Nobody's tough as Jack.
因为杰克确无敌
Now you're getting’ her.
算你们识时务
Like I done told you, singin’ can lighten your terrible load.
我早说过 唱歌能解除你们痛苦的心情
Come one, come all!
快来瞧 快来看
For the fright of your life!
惊险刺激
See the notorious Murrieta Brothers! Robbers, horse thieves...
百年不遇 看看大名时里的 莫瑞耶塔兄弟 抢劫犯 盗马贼
bandits...people of the worst sort!
土匪 人世间最最下流的东西
Hey, gather ‘round!
大家快来看啊
Gracia.
加西亚
It's the Murrieta Brothers.
他们正是莫瑞耶塔兄弟
Get over here, you mangy...trash.
你们跟我过来 人潮
Con su permiso, amigo?
纳丁先生让我看看行吗
These men are now in the custody of Corporal Armando Garcia,
这两个人现在 由我阿曼德。加西亚下士接管了
and we will take them the rest of the way.
我们负责押送他们去监狱
And you can claim your bounty in Tlaxco.
你可以到特拉斯柯领赏了
Yeah, when bulls start wearin’ bloomers.
是吗 你才知道我能领到什么
-How much are we worth? -Get out.
我们值多少钱
All figured...about two hundred pesos.
你一共值两百比索
Two hundred pesos? That's it?
两百比索
After all the payrolls we've robbed?
就这么点
A lousy two hundred pesos apiece, that's all we're worth?
我们抢过成千上万 我们就值两百比索
-We're wasting time. -That's two hundred pesos...
别浪费时间 就两百比索
for the both of you.
而且是两个
What? Are you crazy? Don't take it, Jack!
什么 你疯了吗 去他妈的杰克
Touch my brother again...
别碰我的兄弟 否则的话
and I'll kill you.
我就宇了你
Yes, he will.
他可不是开玩笑
Hey...I thought you were tied up.
我以为你们被绑着呢
That's because you are stupid.
因为你是蠢货
Drop it! Drop it!
放下枪
Hey.
嘿
They got a strongbox on the wagon.
马车上有一个保险箱
We know. That's why we came.
我们知道 就是冲它来的
Lousy two hundred pesos.
才两百比索
That cheat. It is the fact that I,
真差劲 实际上
the legendary Three-Fingered Jack, ain't even mentioned.
我就是传说中的那个三指杰克
l ain't even mentioned.
这谁都知道我就是
And ain't I the one
这不用我说
that figured to kidnap the mayor from his own outhouse?
难道不是我策划了
I tell you. lam the holy guts of this gang.
在市长家里绑架他的计划吗 告诉你们我是这个团伙的灵魂
Without me, the whole dang opera falls apart.
要是没有我 再好的计划也得泡汤
Amigos...adios.
再见了 走好
Just go!
快起来
Come on. Get up, get up!
起来 快点 快走
Go.
走
] want you to know...
你要知道
I consider this an honor.
我非常荣幸
Bury the body. Bag the head.
尸体埋掉 把头带走
Of course I have feelings for you.
木丝娜我依然爱你
Yes, yes, but quick...hide in the barn.
是的 快点你丈夫来了 刀马。 就金
He's coming.
快点
What do you want?
你们是谁
Please! Don't touch me.
想干什么 我求你们
What do you want? Who are you?
千万别杀我 你们是什么人 干什么
Don Rafael.
是拉斐尔先生
Listen to me.
你们听着
If any one of you is, or ever was that masked man all...
如果你们有谁是 或者曾经是那个蒙面人
dressed in black, known as Zorro...
穿着一身黑衣服叫佐罗
reveal himself now!
马上站出来
lam Zor...ro!
我是佐罗
They took my mask...
西班牙人抢走我的面具
-...my sword, my horse! -Silence...you old fool!
我的剑 我的马 住口 厦货
lam Zorro! ! am the man you want!
我才是佐罗 我是你们要找的人
-l am the original...the first! -Liar! Liar!
我是真正的佐罗
-l am the root! -Anyone can see you are too...tall!
你撒谎谁都知道 佐罗没有你那么高的个子
lam Zorro! l am the Zorro!
我是佐罗
Get him out of here...
趁他没发臭
before he starts to stink.
拖出去埋了
Did you find him?
找到他了吗
He's dead.
他死了
Back to the boat.
回到船上去吧
I need some sleep before landing tomorrow.
明天登陆前我要睡上一觉
The governor has returned!
我们的总督大人回来了
Luiz.
路易斯
Welcome home, Rafael. It has been too long.
欢迎回家拉斐尔 时间太久了
Too long, my friend.
是太久了
You said once you favored me above all.
我曾经怀疑过你对我的信任
Consider this...a fool's apology for ever doubting you.
现在就用这块金子 来表达我的歉意吧
Come.
请吧
A crowd has gathered to greet you.
大家都在等着欢迎你了
-Don Pedro. -Don Rafael, welcome.
佩得罗先生 拉斐尔先生
-You're looking well. -Thank you.
欢迎你 你气色不错
-Don Hector. -Welcome back, sir.
海克特先生 欢迎回来
-Don Julio. -Bienvenido a casa.
朱利亚 欢迎你回来
Gentlemen.
先生们
Please, please!
静一静 静一静
I know that you are not really happy to see me.
我知道你们并不高兴看到我回来
So let us all stop pretending, shall we?
就让我们开诚布公 好不好
You think I don't know that... you've been paid...
别以为我不知道他们靠金钱
even threatened, to come out in the hot sun and greet me?
甚至是靠威胁 逼着你们站在烈日下欢迎我
l understand exactly how you feel.
我很清楚的知道 你们现在心里在想什么
Why should you care about any of your leaders,
为什么你们
past or present?
要停留于过去
What did they ever do for you?
或者现在的统治者呢 他们究竟为你们做过什么
The Spaniards oppressed you... the Mexicans ignored you,
西班牙人压迫你们 墨西哥人漠视你们
and the dons, well, the dons, the dons...
而贵族呢 贵族
The don's seem merely content to cheat and lie to you.
这些贵族 他们似乎只满足于撒谎 和欺骗你们
In fact, I put it to you...
总之我要问你们
Who in your entire history has ever helped you?
历史上曾经有谁 帮助过你们
Zorro! Zorro fought for the people.
佐罗 佐罗为人民战斗过
Yes, Zorro.
是啊 佐罗
Where is he now, Padre...
可如今他在哪
your masked friend?
你那个带面具的朋友呢
Unless I'm mistaken,
据我所知
he hasn't shown himself in twenty years.
他已经销声匿迹了20年
Twenty years!
20年
People of California,
加利福尼亚的人民
the time has come to take our destiny into our own hands.
现在到了自己掌握命运的时候了
Not as Spaniards, not as Mexicans, but as Californians!
我们不做西班牙人 不做墨西哥人 要做加利福尼亚人
I stand here before you today... with no mask.
今天我站在你们面前没有面具
Only a pledge.
只有一个承诺
Asolemn pledge that I will never abandon you!
我郑重承诺 我永远不会抛弃你们
And you have my word,
相信我的话
the word of Rafael Montero,
相信拉斐尔。 蒙特罗
that I will do everything within my power to help you fight
我要用毕生的精力为你们
for a free and independent California!
带来一个自由的 完全独立的加利福尼亚
Father!
父亲
Gentlemen,
先生们
allow me to introduce my daughter, Elena.
请容我介绍我的女儿伊莲娜
Thank you.
谢谢
Can anyone tell me what this flower is?
谁能告诉我这是什么花
I know this scent.
我闻过这种花香
Si senorita. It's called Romneya.
尊敬的小姐 这是马针嗣桶
But it only grows in California.
它只生长在加利福尼亚
And I believe this is your first visit to our shores.
我知道你是第一次踏上我们的土地
Yes.
是的
More whiskey.
再来杯威士忌
Or whatever you call this.
随便什么都行
I don't want to see the bottom of this glass, eh?
我可不想守着空杯子
Money first.
先拿钱来
Wait, wait, wait.
等等
What about this?
这个怎么样
Silver.
银的
Of course, silver. The finest.
当然是银的 最纯银子
Where did you get that?
从哪弄来的
It's none of your business.
你少管闲事
Where did you get it?
我问你哪来的
It was my brother's.
是我哥哥的
He's dead.
他死了
I'm sorry.
我很难过
You're sorry?
你难过
Why should you be sorry?
你难过什么
You should not trade something like that for a mere glass of whiskey.
你不应该用这样的东西 换一杯威士鼠
Why not?
为什么
You think I could get two?
你觉得它能换两杯 是吗
Who's that?
他是谁
That's the man who killed my brother.
他是杀害我哥哥的凶手
You're drunk and you're angry,
你喝栈了
in no condition to fight a professional soldier.
而且在气头上 不是职业士兵的对手
Get out of my way, old man.
别挡我的路 老头
Would you care to try again?
还想不想再来
You're welcome.
用不着客气
For what?
客气什么
For saving your life.
我救了你一命
I would have killed him.
你救了他的命
No, not today. He is trained to kill.
不 我救了你 他是职业杀手
You seem trained to drink.
而你是职业酒鬼
Yes, my friend,
没错 我的朋友
you would have fought very bravely and died very quickly.
你很勇敢 但只要一交手
Who, then, would avenge your brother?
你就会死在他的刀下 到那时谁为你哥哥复仇
[ would have found a way.
打死他
I've never lost a fight.
我从来没有输过
Except to a crippled old man, just now.
你刚刚还输给一个不中用的老头
What is your name?
你叫什么名字
-Alejandro.
阿利亚多
You know there is a saying, a very old saying...
你知道从前有名老话说得好
"When the pupil is ready, the master will appear."
当你需要知识的时候
Now, if you want to kill this man,
老师就会出现
I can help you and I can teach you how.
如果你想杀死那个人
How to move, how to think,
我现在就可以教你怎么做
how to take your revenge with honor and...
我会教你如何行动 如何思想
live to celebrate it.
如何报仇
But it will take dedication.
但那需要献身精神
It will take time.
需要时间
Why are you so eager to help me?
你为什么要热心帮有我
Because once, a long time ago...
因为有一次 很久以前了
you did the same for me.
你也帮过我
I can't believe it.
真想不到
I never thought that one day...
真想不到有一天
] would be standing in the lair of the fox.
我会站在这个神秘的洞穴中
In the lair of Zorro.
佐罗的洞穴
Yeah...this place was devoted to the training of Zorro.
这里是佐罗诞生的地方
Where were you all these years?
这些年你去哪了
I thought you were dead.
我以为你死了
I was dead...
我的确死过
and we will leave it at that.
咱们先不谈这个
l remember last time I saw you, in the square.
我还记得上次在广场看你的情景
Fighting a hundred men.
当时你以一挡百
-A hundred men? -l cannot forget.
以一挡百
You were the greatest swordsman who zer lived.
我永远都忘不了 你是世界上最伟大的剑客
Yes.
没错
Rafael Montero was the governor of California then.
那时候拉斐尔。 蒙特罗 还是加利福尼亚的总督
Do you remember him?
你还记得他吗
What?
什么
Rafael Montero, do you remember him?
拉斐尔。 蒙特罗 对他还有印象吗
Yes...his soldiers killed many...
是的 他的士兵滥杀无奉
and, he was the sworn enemy of Zorro.
他是佐罗不共戴天的死政
You.
就是你
Montero's come back.
蒙特罗又回来了
Good.
太好了
Then you can kill him.
你可以把他干掉
No, there are...complications,
不行 情况非常复杂
too many complications for me to ignore.
千万不能轻举妄动
What complications?
什么情况
I can see we're not gonna spend much time talking.
你好像不太喜欢谈论自己的事
Montero has some plan, some...
蒙特罗有个阴谋
design for California.
针对加利福尼亚的阴谋
Otherwise, he would not have retained
否则他不会
the services of your Captain Love.
出钱请了个 与你不共戴天勒福上尉
We must find out what that design is.
我们必须搞清想他的阴谋
And then what?
然后呢
If you are ready...
如果你已经做好了准备
we will both tempt our fates.
我们就开始复仇吧
Let's go then!
那就干吧
Do you know how to use that thing?
你知道用剑的要领吗
The pointy end goes into the other man.
剑锋要指向对手
Yeah.
是吗
This is going to take a lot of work.
事情可没那么简单
This is called a training circle, a master's wheel.
这个圆圈就是训练场地 岂大师圆轮
This circle will be your world, your whole life.
这个圆圈就是你的一切 你的生命
Until I tell you otherwise, there is nothing outside of it.
在我发话以前 它的外面一无所有
-Capitan Love is out... -There is nothing...outside of it.
可外面有勒福 一无所有 在它的外面
Captain Love does not exist until l say he exists.
等我说有勒福上尉这个人时 他才存在
As your skill with the sword improves...
随着剑术的不断提高
you will progress to a...smaller circle.
你的圆圈就会越来越小
With each new circle, your world contracts,
圆圈越小
bringing you that much closer to your adversary,
你的世界就越小 你和对手的距离就越来越近
that much closer to retribution.
报仇就指日可待
I like that part.
我就盼着这一天
Shall we?
开始吗
Slow!
要慢
Attack slow.
进攻要慢
Attack!
进攻
Slow. Again!
慢 进攻
Slow!
慢
Let's try and...slow, like...Good.
再来 慢 很好
Good...that is good.
很好 非常漂亮
Thank you.
谢谢
Attack.
进攻
Good.
好的
Time for a drink.
休息一会
Perfect. Do it again.
好极了 再来一次
One, five, three!
一五三
Six, four, two!
六四二
And lunge!
冲刺
Over-lunged!
过头了
Lesson number one...
第一课
never attack in anger.
进攻时不能斗气
Lesson number two...
这第二课. . .
Come with me.
跟我来
What?
怎么啦
So what is lesson number three?
第三课是什么
To get to lesson number four.
就是活着上第四课
Again?
再来
A black Andalusian.
一匹西班牙良种马
Magnificent.
是匹宝马
Looks like your old horse, Tornado.
就像你当年的黑旋风
Quiet, quiet.
安静 安静
Damn horse!
该死的畜生
What are you doing, huh?
你想干什么
I'll see you tonight.
咱们今天晚上见
Zorro, you look better than ever.
佐罗 一个全新的佐罗
Be careful, senorita.
当心一点 小姐
There are dangerous men about.
有人在打你的主意
Well, if you see any, be sure to point them out.
是吗 要是你看见他就告诉我一声
Okay, everybody's in.
好啊 全押上了
Don Burrite...
开始吧
Listen.
听着
I'm going to give you the great honor of being my horse.
你就要很荣幸的 成为我的坐骑了
We are...like one spirit.
我们是不可分割的整体
Damn it! Stop!
停住 快停住
Go, go...go, go!
加 力吕 力D 马 马 马
Get him!
抓住他
Kill him.
弄死他
The legend has returned!
佐罗 一个传琳的复活
Don't yell.
别出声
I need sanctuary, Father.
我喜欢神的庇护 神父
-You don't know me, so... -Zorro? Of course I know you.
你不认识我了吗 佐罗 我当然认识你
Zorro, is it really you?
真的是你吗
I must say the years
上月
have been far kinder to you than they have been to me.
对你真是格外的宽容
I'm sorry, I have no time for talk now.
对不起 我没有时间跟你解释了
Father, please...hide me.
神父 请你掩护
Just like the old days.
咱们一切照旧
Padre, is that you?
神父 是你吗
It sounds like there is a battle going on out there.
外面好像正在打侈
Don't worry, my dear.
别担心 亲爱的
You are safe in the house of the Lord.
在上帝家里你是安全的
Of course, Padre.
当然 神父
Forgive me, Father, for have sinned.
请宽架我吧 ”神父
It has been three days since my last confession.
宽恕我的罪孽 三天前
Three days.
我曾经性悔过
How many sins could you have committed in three days?
才过了三天你能犯什么罪
Come back when you've had more time, please.
等你真犯了罪 再来吧
Excuse me?
你说什么
Listen, senorita...
听着尊贵的小姐
please...go on.
请你说下去
I have broken the Fourth Commandment, Padre.
我违反了十戒中的第四条
You killed somebody?
你杀人了
No, that is not the Fourth Commandment.
不 那应该是第六条
Of course not.
对 当然是
You...in what way did you break the most sacred...
可是你是怎么触犯了神圣的十戒呢
..of commandments?
告诉我
I dishonored my father.
我让父亲蒙受了羞辱
That is not so bad.
那不是仕么坏事
Maybe your father deserved it.
也许你父亲罪有应得
What did you say?
你说什么
I said, tell me more...my child.
我是说你接着说吧 我的孩子
Well, I try to behave properly, the way my father would like me to.
我一直想做个好女孩 就像父亲要求我的那样
But I'm afraid my heart is too wild.
只是我的心有点太野了
Too wild?
太野了
Yes.
是的
Could you be a little more specific about that?
你能不能说得再具体一点
I had impure thoughts about a man.
我对一个男人起了杂念
I did. I think he was a bandit or something.
是真的我想他是一个菲徒
He wore a black mask.
他头上戴着黑面具
He had a...a deep voice?
而且声音低沉
Yes.
是的
Ruggedly handsome?
他还仪表堂堂
I do not know. His face was half covered.
我不知道他的脸挡住了一半
But something in his eyes captured me.
但他的眼睛紧紧的抓住了我的心
Captured you?
你的心
l felt warm and feverish.
他使我感到情不自禁
Lustful?
欲火上身
Yes, lustful.
是的 欲火上身
Forgive me.
宽恕我吧
l forgive you.
我宽恕你
Look over there, by the altar!
你们去圣坛里面找
Search everything!
彻底搜查
The chapel, the loft, the rectory...all of it!
祈祷室 楼厢 包括住所
This is a house of God.
全面搜查 这里可是上帝的家
Don't worry, Padre.
别担心 神父
We'll be gone by the time He gets back.
等上帝回来我们就走
Senorita...
伊莲娜
..you have done nothing wrong.
你并没有犯罪
The only sin would be to deny what your heart truly feels.
真正的犯罪 那是违背你自己的真实情感
Now go!
快走吧
Elena!
伊莲娜
What are you doing here?
你来这儿干什么
I was confessing.
我来尾悔
-Confessing? -Yes.
性悔 是的
To whom? The priest is here.
向谁尾悔 神父在这
Stand back, Elena.
让开 伊莲娜
Please.
请让开
Out of respect for Miss Montero...
这是对蒙特罗小姐的不敬
I'll deal with you later.
等会再和你算账
Horse!
马儿
Blackie!
黑子
Storm!
风暴
Stupido, get over here now!
笨蛋 到这边来 快点
I warn you...I'll get another horse.
你小心一点 我可要找别的马了
So...what do you think?
你看我干得怎么样
Sir, sir!
先生 先生
I got the black stallion.
我搞到了一匹马
I carved a "2" in the...
还在兵营里刻上了字母 Z
Don...Diego,
狄葛先生
the people will be speaking the name of Zorro again.
人民又会重新谈论起 佐罗的事迹来
You think stealing a horse
你以为偷了一匹马
and scratching marks in a wall makes you
再刻上一个字
worthy enough to wear that mask?
就能戴那个面具了吗
Be careful.
担心点
You're a thief, Alejandro.
你是个贼 阿利亚多
A pitiful clown.
一个可怜的家伙
Zorro was a servant of the people.
佐罗是人民的公仆
He was not a seeker of fame, like you.
不像你是个沽名钓誉的小人
A buffoon.
一个小丑
Zorro did what was needed.
佐罗在需要的时候才会出现
And now he's needed again.
现在人民就需要他
I didn't ask for your help in the cantina.
当初在酒吧里 我并没让你帮有我
But I came here to learn how to fight like you.
我到这来 是向你学习如何进行战斗
To have your strength, your courage.
从你这里获得力量和勇气
Now when I try to use them, you slap me down?
可当我大显身手时 你却跟我浚冷水
Let me tell you something...
实话告诉你吧
1 am tired of all your training, your lecturing.
我早就厌烦了 你的训练和没完没了的说教
lam tired of waiting for you to tell me I am ready.
我再也不想等你的命令 我准备好了
I have my own scores to settle.
我有深仇大恨要报
A new life to find.
我要寻找新的生活
I thought I could do it here...
我以为你能帮有我
but I was wrong.
可我错了
Alejandro!
阿利亚多
En garde!
看剑
Choose your weapon.
你选择武器吧
Montero has invited every don in California
蒙特罗已经 把加利福尼亚所有的贵族
to a banquet at his hacienda.
请到了他的庄园
If you want to be of service you can join them as a spy.
如果你想为人民做事 那就不妨混进他的内部
[ think I do not understand, sir.
我好像不太明白你的意思 先生
You have passion, Alejandro, and your skill is growing.
你有热情 阿利亚多 你的剑术也有长进
But to enter Montero's world, I must give you something...
要想打进蒙特罗的圈子
which is completely beyond your reach.
你还得向我学学 你完全不懂的东西
Oh, yes? And what is that?
是吗 学什么东西
Charm.
风度
Convince Montero that you're a gentleman of stature,
要让蒙特罗相信 你是个有身份的绅士
and he will let you into his circle.
那样你才能被他接纳
Me?
我
Agentleman?
一个绅士
This is going to take a lot of work.
那可不是容易的事
Look at me.
看看我
look like a butterfly.
像只花蝴蝶
This is the most stupid thing I've ever done.
这一定是我干过的最思春的事吧
-We'll never get away with this. -Yes, we will.
我看这事没谱 没问题
Anobleman is nothing but a man
当个贵族没什么难的
who says one thing and thinks another.
只要说一套做一套就行了
What if Montero realizes who you are?
要是蒙特罗认出你怎么办
Montero thinks of himself as a true nobleman.
蒙特罗自认为是个真正的贵族
He will never look a servant in the eye.
他对仆人根本不屑一顾
Listen to me.
你听我说
Listen to me!
听我说
The most important thing of all...
有一件事情最为重要
Do not let the dons leave the table without you.
不要被其他贵族单独留在餐桌上
Yes.
好的
Good.
那就好
And good luck tonight.
祝你今晚好运
Thank you.
谢谢
Stand up straight.
站直一些
Charm.
风度
Don Rafael Montero?
拉斐尔。蒙特罗先生
Good evening.
晚上好
lam Don Alejandro del Castillo y Garcia.
我是阿利亚多。卡斯提诺。加西亚
The formal greeting of the Spanish court.
这种西班牙宫廷的见面礼
I have not seen that in years.
我有好久不见了
My father was very strict in matters of etiquette.
我父亲在礼仪方面对我非常严格
And who is your father?
请问令尊是.. .
Don Bartolo del Castillo.
巴特史。卡斯提诺
I have heard of Don Bartolo,
我听说过他的名字
but I've never had the pleasure of meeting him.
只是无缘和他见面
l arrived last week from Spain, by way of Paris,
上周我刚从西班牙转到巴黎
Lisbon and San Francisco.
里斯本和旧金山来到此地
lam inspecting my family's holdings.
我来视察家传的产业
Queen Isabella of Spain has been...
西班牙伊莎贝拉女王
very generous to us.
对我们家恩惠有加
Very impressive.
真令人羡幕
What brings you to my door?
什么风把你吹到了寒舍
When I heard you were back in California,
我听说你又回到了加利福尼亚
I knew I...must introduce myself.
所以特地登门拜访
Her Royal Highness speaks very highly of you.
女王可是对你评价甚高
Really?
是吗
I was out of favor with the Spanish court
已经失去了宫廷厚爱
since alifornia was lost to Mexico.
因为加利福尼亚 落入了墨西哥人之手
Only in certain circles.
只是部分人对你有微辞
Her Majesty knows
女王陛下
those unfortunate events were clearly no fault of yours.
深知这种不幸非你一人之过
She also told me this province
她还说对有远见的人来讲
is still a land of opportunity for a man of vision.
这个省份仍然充满了机会
And you are a man of vision?
你就很有远见
lam a man...in search of a vision.
我只是个到此地来淘金的人
But my timing is unfortunate.
不过我好像来得不是时候
[ have interrupted a party.
很抱歉我扰了你的聚会
Perhaps I could call again.
也许我还是改日再来
No, no, it would, honor me for you to join us.
不 不 如果你留下 我就不甚荣幸
It would honor me to do so, sir.
我真是求之不得 尊散的先生
Please, allow me tointroduce my daughter...Elena.
请允许我 介绍自己的女儿
Charmed.
不胜荣幸
I'm afraid I have brought no gift for the hostess.
可惜我没有给小姐带什么礼物来
But...wait a moment.
没关系 请等一下
Thank you.
谢谢
My pleasure.
不客气
Bernardo...pick up your feet.
伯纳德 跟我来吧
Senorita.
小姐
Caballero.
先生
Don Alejandro.
阿利亚多先生
My father and I would like you to join us at our table.
父亲和我希望你到我们餐桌来
I would be delighted, senorita.
我受宠若惊 小姐
Don Alejandro, I'm so pleased you could join us.
阿利亚多先生 非常高兴和你共聚一堂
Gentlemen, allow me
先生们
to introduce Don Alejandro del Castillo y Garcia,
请允许我介绍 阿利亚多。卡斯提诺。加西亚先生
recently returned from Spain.
他刚刚从西班牙来
This is, Captain Harrison Love.
这位是哈里森。勒福上尉
Not a don, but... certainly a kindred spirit.
他不是贵族 但具有贵族精神
Are you not the man
前几天
who was chasing a legendary bandit recently?
穷追那个传奇菲徒的人 不就是你吗
He was hardly legendary.
我不认为他有什么传硼
So you caught him?
抓到他了
It's only a matter of time.
那只是时间问题
Well, the bandit may have escaped,
看来你让他逃掉了
but the rest of us will certainly think twice
我们这些人以后再去教堂性悔时
before going to confession.
可得三思而行
Thank you.
多谢了
With all due respect, Don Hector, I disagree.
如我直言海克特先生 我不这么认为
Until these people are free to... govern themselves,
在人民获得真正自由之前
I think we will see many more "Z's carved into walls.
我们还会在墙壁上 看到更多的Z标记
Don Alejandro, what do you think?
阿利亚多先生 你怎么看
I think...the sheep will always need a shepherd.
我想 羊群总是需要领头的
But, certainly not this... Zorro creature.
但是领头羊绝不是 这个叫佐罗的家伙
He probably wears the mask
他戴着面具
to hide his bald head and unsightly features.
也许只是为了遮住他的秃头 或是丑陋的面容
There are some who would call him heroic.
可很多人都称他为英雄
Heroism. A romantic illusion.
英雄主义那只是浪漫幻觉
-Much like nobility? -Elena, that is enough.
就像贵族一样 伊莲娜够了
Myself, I would think heroism is...
以我之见英雄主义
something to aspire to, not sneer at.
应该受到鼓励而不是嘲弄
All that playing with swords...
那些只不过是比剑
shooting guns, racing around with horses.
对射 骑马 追逐等等
Gives me a frightful headache.
一想起来头都会大了
Such sweaty pursuits are... hardly the work of a gentleman.
一个绅士不应该在这方面有所追求
And what is?
那追求什么
Climbing in and out of carriages?
在马车上钻进钻出
No, my dear.
不 亲爱的
But increasing one's holdings
一个绅士应该追求更多的财富
so as to provide lavish comfort for ladies...
以便让小姐们过得更舒服一些
such as yourself.
比如说你
A woman's grasp of politics. What can I say?
伊莲娜不懂什么是政治多有得罪
Well, we're at a party, aren't we?
这只是一次聚会对吗
Elena...may I have the honor of this dance?
伊茵娜 这一曲可以请你跳吗
[ would be glad to.
我非常愿意
Yes?
你好
Were you looking for something?
在找什么东西吗
Asense of the miraculous in everyday life.
在我平庸的生活中 寻找的亮丽
Oh, really?
是吗
Well, why don't you try looking someplace else?
可你为什么不到别处找找
The lady and ! were trying to dance.
这位小姐正在和我跳舞
You were trying.
你在散步
She was succeeding.
小姐在跳舞
Forgive me, Capitan, a shameless joke at your expense.
对不起 上尉 这是一个无伤大雅的玩笑
And I hope it will not be the last.
希望这不是最后一次
Don Rafael wants you back at his table...
拉斐尔先生在找你 马上
Pino.
拿着
Would you care to try something more, robust?
想不想来点更奔放的 我想你在这方面
Or do you feel unequal to the task?
不会是准备不足吧 小姐
No, on the contrary, Don Alejandro.
不 正相反 阿利亚多先生
I think only of your distaste for perspiration.
我还以为你这个人 不喜欢剧烈的运动
-Maestro... -Si.
指挥
Well, If that's the way they are dancing in Madrid these days...
最近马德里非常流行这种跳法
Excuse me, Don Rafael. I need to catch my breath.
对不起 拉斐尔先生 我得去喘口气了
Your daughter is a very spirited dancer.
你女儿是一个非常有激情的舞者
"Spirited."
有激情
Thank you for putting it so delicately.
谢谢你用了如此文雅的字眼
l apologize if you were offended.
如果你受到了冒犯
Oh, no. Completely unnecessary, l assure you.
不 完全不必 我向你保证
She's and impulsive...
她很年轻 冲动
but her beauty is beyond compare.
但她的美丽无人可比
And she has her father's commanding presence.
而且他具有父亲那种大将风度
Don Rafael?
拉斐尔先生
As...an advisor to Her Royal Highness
作为女王陛下在经济方面的
in matters of finance...
财经顾问
it would be my pleasure to introduce you both at court.
我将很荣幸的把你们介绍给宫廷
Join us in the courtyard.
请跟我来一下
There's something I would like to share with you.
有件事情我想告诉你
What is that?
什么事
Avision.
远见
Fellow dons of California...
加利福尼亚的贵族先生们
all of us here can recall the golden years
谁都不会忘记我们当年统治
when we ruled this country.
这里时的辉煌败月
We commanded respect as noblemen
作为贵族
and we amassed a great deal of wealth.
我们不但受到尊敬 而且非常富有
There was something that we never achieved.
但是有一种权力 我们从来没有得到过
We never determined our own... destiny.
那就是掌握自己的命运
Well...the time has come.
先生们
Time to claim what always should have been ours.
这一天终于来到了
My friends...
我们要争取
I give...you...
早该属于我们的权力
the independent Republic of California.
朋友们 我要给你们 一个独立自主的加利福尼亚共和
Don Rafael...
拉斐尔先生
every man here owes you something.
我们这些人都欠着你的情
The land you gave us made us all wealthy men.
你分给我们的土地 使我们成了富人
However, we must question your motives.
不过我们必须知道你的动机
The day you arrived on the beach you made us all look like fools.
你回来那天在海滩上 把我们大家全都要了
That is absurd, Don Pedro.
这就奇怪了 佩得罗先生
I was merely playing to the crowd.
我那只是演戏而已
And what are you doing now, if not playing to the crowd?
此时您在干嘛 不也是在演戏吗
Now you're inciting us to raise arms against Santa Anna,
您想鼓动我们跟山堪安纳开战
when you know perfectly well we could never defeat his army.
但是您很清楚 我们不可能打败他们的军队
I was not suggesting that we fight him for California.
我并没有说 为了加州要和他们开战
I was suggesting that we buy it... from him.
我打算从她手里买下它
Santa Anna is waging . a very ex...pensive war
山塔安纳正在和美国打一场
with the United States increasingly short of money.
代价极大的战争 她的资金非常紧张
Even if we all... and is combined our fortunes,
可现在就是把我们所有的钱
we could not come up with enough money
全都拿出来
to buy this country from Santa Anna.
也无法凌够买下加州的数额
I have already brokered a deal with him.
我已经和她达成了协议
You're living in a dream, Montero.
你白日做梦 蒙特罗
Then why don't we all live in the same dream together?
我们大家为什么 不一起来做这个梦呢
Meet me here tomorrow morning, gentlemen,
明天一早你们来这里见我
for a journey that will open your eyes
我要带大家开开眼界
and lay all your doubts to rest.
把你们的疑虑彻底打消
My friends, I give you...
朋友们 这里就是.. .
Technically, of course, all this gold be...longs to Santa Anna.
从技术上讲 这些金砖全部属于山堪安纳
But fortunately for us,
但值得庆幸的是
he's completely unaware of its existence.
她根本不知道这个地方的存在
Now, for the deception to work,
为了骗过山卉安纳的眼睛
all these bars have been marked with the Spanish seal,
这些金砖全部打上了西班牙印记
so that he will think they have come from Spain.
她会以为这是从西班牙运来的
You see now, gentlemen? Is it becoming clearer to you?
看到了了吗 先生们 没有什么疑问了吧
Two days from now,
再有两天时间
we will buy this country from Santa Anna.
我们就能从 山塔安纳手里买下加州
And we...will buy it with gold dug from his own land.
而且全部是用她自己的金子
Where did you find these people?
从哪找来这么多人
Anywhere we wanted.
哪都能找到
Brilliant.
很好
It's only part of the mining process.
是开矿的爆破声
First, we were just picking it up off the ground,
最初我们是一点点的控
but now we're down to blasting.
现在我们是用炸药炸
So...is this the future of California?
这就是未来的加利福尼亚共和国
This is my vision, yes.
是的 这是我的梦想
Basura, up here!
蒙特罗 看这
Well, now ain't you a sight for sore eyes!
你们的到来 让我们感到眼前一亮
Full-growed vultures walkin’ around like real folk.
凶恶的蕃骑 大摇大摆的穿上了人的衣服
Welcome!
欢迎你们
Welcome to hell's outhouse.
欢迎你们来到地狱的门前
Now, they call us the disappeared ones.
我们被称作消失的一族
But as you can...see, we ain't exactly disappeared.
可你们看到了我们并没有消失
We just been a little hard to find.
只是不容易找到而已
Wait!
等等
You! I know you.
你 我认识你
You bet you do, peckerwood!
你当然认识我 恶棍
I'm the legendary Three-Fingered Jack!
我就是传说中的三指杰克
And you... are a bunch of murderin' trash...
可你们是一群杀人的恶魔
dressed up in fancy, sweet-smellin' doodads.
只不过外表穿上了华丽的衣尝
Ignore him, gentlemen. He's a common thief.
不要理他 先生们 他是个无耻的强盗
As common as they come.
我是强盗不假
But I ain't nothin’ compared to you gentlemen.
但和你们相比 我自愧不如
I steal gold. ! steal...money.
先生们 我抢夺黄金 抢夺钱财
But you...you steal people's lives.
而你们抢夺人的生命
So damn you...
见鬼去吧
and damn the horse that brung you!
你们通通的见鬼去吧
Peckerwood?
是个恶棍
Is there something... amusing, Captain?
你觉得好笑 是吧 上尉
Strange, I'd say.
我只是觉得奇怪
It's the second time l've shot this man
这是我第二次
while he was flying through the air.
把他从空中击落
Don Alejandro!
阿利亚多先生
I need to speak with you at the hacienda. Alone.
我要和你回庄园谈一谈 你一个人
Some other time. Perhaps.
最好是可以改天
Today. Alone.
就今天 单独谈
Good afternoon, Bernardo.
你好 伯纳德
Good afternoon, senorita.
你好 尊贵的小姐
Your voice is so calming.
你的声音如此平和
He's high-spirited. He needs to hear something soothing.
这马性情暴烈 需要用声音安抚
Yes, l understand.
是的 我明白
How long have you served Don Alejandro?
你为阿利亚多先生当差多久了
Sometimes it seems interminable.
有时候连我自己都说不清了
I'm sorry, l speak out of place.
对不起 我不应该这样讲
Do not worry, Bernardo.
没关系 伯纳德
He will not hear it from me.
我不会告诉他的
Don Alejandro confuses me.
我真猜不透阿利亚多先生
Sometimes he seems so arrogant, so superior.
有时他好像傲慢无理 目空一切 不过. . .
And yet, the way that he looks at me and...
他看我时的眼神
the way that he dances with me...
还有他跟我跳舞时的样子
as if he were two completely different men.
又让我觉得简直判若两人
You look so much like your mother.
你长得真像你母亲
How would you know that?
你怎么会知道
Well...l don't see much of Don Rafael in you.
因为我在你身上 看不到拉斐尔先生的影子
I know my father wishes l acted more like her.
我知道父亲希望我的举止像母亲
She was very proper... my mother, always appropriate.
非常高尚 她是一个完美无缺的女人
Is that how he describes her?
这是拉斐尔说的吗
Yes, but sometimes I do not believe him.
是的 可有时候我并不相信他
She was more like you.
你母亲更像你
Perhaps.
可能吧
It would be a way of knowing her.
那样更容易了解她
My ninera once told me
我的保姆曾经对我说
that the departed can see you in the moonlight.
去世的人能在月光下看见你
So when I was young,
所以我小时候
l used to sneak out of my window at night
常常在夜里礁窗溜出去
and ride my horse across Andalusia.
骑上马 窜过安大路西亚
And would wave at the sky, so she would know it was me.
一边骑 一边招手 好让她能认出我来
How did she die?
你母亲怎么死的
Giving birth to me.
生我时难产
My father rarely speaks of her. I think he finds it too painful.
父亲很少说起她 我想他一定很痛苦
Yes.
是的
I know what it is like to lose a...
我也党到过失去亲人的
a loved one.
滋味
You?
你
Yeah, a daughter...long ago.
一个女儿 很久以前
When I see you, I remember what it...
看到你 我就想起了
felt like to be a father.
作为一个父亲当时的心情
I'm sure your mother would be very proud of you, senorita.
我敢说你母亲一定为你感到骄傲
Thank you,
谢谢
Bernardo. I have to ask you... have we ever met before?
伯纳德 我必须问一下 我们以前见过面吗
No. Why would you think that?
没有 你为什么那样想
I do not know. It's strange.
不知道 我也奇怪
Your voice seems so familiar, somehow.
不过你的声音我听着很熟
But haven't been to Spain since before you were born.
从你出生前直到现在 我从没去过西班牙
Of course.
那当然
Well, it's a very pleasant voice.
总之你的声音很动听
Thank you.
谢谢
Good day, Bernardo.
再见 伯纳德
Good day...
再见
Elena.
伊莲娜
Did you know that the Compa Indians of central Peru used to...
听说过秘鲁中部的土族印第安人
cannibalize their slain enemies in order to absorb their power?
经常会吃掉他们的敌人 以便获取他们身上的力量吗
The eyes, in particular, were most sought after.
眼睛是他们最喜欢吃的部位
To be able to see through the eyes of an enemy...
能够用敌人的眼睛观察敌人
is a valuable thing.
是非常重要的
Where are my manners?
我的礼瑶哪去了
Would you...Would you care for something to drink?
想不想喝点什么
No?
不喜欢
A different vintage, perhaps?
那就换个口味怎么样
You're a very sick person, Capitan Love.
你是个变态的人 勒福上尉
Heads in water jars, hands in wine pitchers must,
水瓶里有头 酒瓶里有手 阁下
... Strike you as odd. ] suppose.
一定把你吓得不轻
Well, for one thing...
我是担心
I think you ought to fire your housekeeper.
会吓着你的管家
Who is he?
他是谁
An enemy.
一个敌人
He has a brother out there who will share the same fate.
他还有一个弟弟 也会得到同样的下场
I wish you luck.
好啊 祝你走运
To your health.
为你健康
Murrieta's brother or not...
不管是不是莫瑞耶塔的弟弟
you are more than you pretend to be.
肯定是个有背景的人
Maybe someday...
也许有一天
! will see what ! look like through your eyes...
我会用你的眼睛看看我是什么人
Capitan Love.
勤福上尉
Oh, it is beautiful.
太漂亮了
Excuse me...how much does it cost?
请问这个多少钱
It is a gift, she says... in honor of your mother.
她说这是送给你的礼物 是为了你母亲
My mother?
我母亲
She loved your mother.
她很喜欢你母亲
No, tell her she must be mistaken.
不对 她一定搞错了
My mother died long ago in Spain.
我母亲去世多年了
She says there's no mistaking
她说你肯定是
the daughter of Esperanza and Diego de la Vega.
爱佩莎和狄葛的女儿 她说她以前.. .
She says she was your nanny.
曾经当过你的保姆
She hung flowers on your crib when you were little.
还说小时候把花挂在你的摇篮里
I'm sorry, l cannot accept it.
对不起 我不能接受
Alejandro?
阿利亚多
Alejandro, listen to me.
听我说 阿利亚多
Can you find your way back to the mine?
你还能找到去金矿的路吗
No.
不能
The carriage windows were all covered.
马车窗户挡得严严实实
He didn't even trust his own dons.
他连那些贵族也不相信
Nor would I.
我也一样
You must go to Montero's house tonight.
今天你必须去蒙特罗庄园走一趟
Break into the chest in his study.
你要打开那书房中的文件柜
Find anything that will tell us what his plans are...
找到一些能说明他计划的东西
People in the mine are dying...
矿工们正走向死亡
and...all 1 can think of is...
可是我眼前只有一个
Capitan Love.
勒福上校
He will come into your circle soon enough.
他早晚会落入你的手心
You need not chase him.
用不着操之过急
We lose the ones we love.
我们都曾失去过亲人
We cannot change it. Put it aside.
振作起来
How?
怎么振作
How can I do what is needed, when all I feel is...hate?
我知道人民需要我 可我只有一个念头 报仇
You hide it...
藏起仇恨
with this.
用这个
Santa Anna has agreed to the transfer at noon,
山塔安纳已经同意后天中午交市
the day after tomorrow.
但她坚持要我们把黄金运到
But he insists we deliver the gold five miles north of town.
城北五英里处
Captain Love?
勒福上校
I's a safe distance from the mine.
那里处在安全区之外
The bars are stamped and ready.
金砖已经打好了标记 准备妥当
I don't foresee a problem.
我看没有问题
Tell him we agree.
告诉他 我们同意
You've done well, Luiz, very well.
你干得很出色 路易斯 非常出色
To the independent Republic of California.
为独立的加利福尼亚共和国
Don Rafael!
拉斐尔先生
Did you send men to the hills? Double the guard at the wall?
山上是不是派了人 墙上是不是增加了警戒
Yes, yes, of course.
是的 是的当然
After all, it's only one man.
他毕竟只有一个人
It isn't just one man, damn it! It's Zorro.
谁说只有一个人 见鬼 可他是佐罗
And he knows about the mine.
而且他知道了金矿的事
Otherwise he wouldn't be here tonight.
不然今晚就不会来了
-How could he possibly... -It doesn't matter how.
他怎么可能知道 那已经无关紧要了
You don't seem to grasp the... situation, Captain.
你好像还没有意识到 问题的严重性
lf Santa Anna...finds out
要是山卉安纳知道
that we have paid him in gold stolen from his own land,
我们用她士地上的金子付账
he will have us butchered like cattle.
她会把我们千刀万出
Do you understand?
明白吗
Then we should destroy the evidence.
我们必须销毁证据
Set explosives, bury the mine.
埋放炸药炸毁金矿
And the workers?
那些工人呢
We destroy all the evidence, Don Rafael.
所有证据全部销毁 拉斐尔先生
No witnesses.
不留活口
Make sure those papers are locked up.
这些文件一定要锁好
Guards!
卫兵
The much-debated Zorro.
你就是车事生非的佐罗
No.
不
The legendary Zorro.
是传奇式的佐罗
Put down your weapons!
放下武器
Tell them.
下命令
Do as he says!
照他说的做
Allow me.
对不起了
Stop.
站住
Face the window.
面对墙壁
Now...bend down and touch your toes.
现在把腰弯下 手摸着脚
Bend over.
快弯下腰
Would you excuse me, Capitan Love?
请让开好吗 上和尉
Thank you.
谢谢
Alto!
不要跑
Kill him.
杀死他
Good morning, senor.
早上好 先生
Good morning, senorita.
早上好 小姐
Give it back.
还给我
What?
什么
Whatever it is you have stolen from my father.
不管你偷了我父亲什么 我现在
] want it back. Give it to me.
都要你把它还给我
No.
不还
Come on, now.
别胡疗
I don't have the time to give you the proper instruction.
我可没有时间给你上剑术课
I have had the proper instruction since I was four.
我四岁时就已经上过剑术课
Not bad.
还行吗
Not bad at all.
漂亮极了
This will make it more difficult,
这回不太好亲你了
senori...ta.
尊贵的小姐
Don't move.
请别动
Do you surrender?
你服输吗
Never.
绝不
But l may scream.
但我会喊叫
l understand.
我能理解
Sometimes I have that effect.
有时我也想喊叫
Excuse me.
对不起了
Goodbye, senorita.
后会有期 小姐
What are you doing here? What happened?
你在这干什么 出了什么事
Zorro.
佐罗
Zorro was here. I fought him, and he left.
佐罗来过这 我和他比剑
He left!
后来他走了
Do you recognize him?
你看清楚了吗
No. But he was and vigorous.
没有 不过他非常年轻 非常 .
He was very vigorous, Father.
他非常强壮
Vigorous?
强壮
Yes.
是的
Let's go!
上路吧
Go!
力口 马
Here...this is the canyon.
这 第一条峡谷
That is where the mine is.
金库就在里面
They have...twenty five, thirty guards at most.
他们已经派了至少30多个警卫
Nothing that Zorro can't overcome.
再多也不是我们的对手
I'm not going with you.
我不能和你去
What?
什么
There's something I must do. It's a personal matter.
有件事我必须要去办 是一件私事
What about the prisoners?
那些囚犯怎么办
There's nothing more I can do for them.
我实在没有办法帮助他们了
You mean, nothing you will do.
就是说你撤手不管了
I gave my life to them!
我为他们奋斗了一生
And in return, I lost everything.
落了个家破人亡
My wife was murdered before my eyes
眼陷陷的看着我妻子死去
and my child was stolen to be raised by my mortal enemy.
我女儿被仇敌抢去养大成人
Montero?
蒙特罗
Elena.
伊莲娜
She's your daughter.
她是你女儿
Yes, she was.
她是我女儿
So...
这么说吧
you will simply take your revenge.
你是要去报仇了
No. ! will take my daughter.
不 我要去找我女儿
And don't pretend she means nothing to you.
不要假装她对你无所谓
But you taught me to see beyond personal feelings, remember?
可你告诉我要 超越个人感情 忘了吗
Was that all a lie?
难道你在骗我
-You're too to understand. -To understand what?
你太年轻 无法理解 无法理解什么
Betrayal?
背叛
All the work, all the training, all the wise words.
所有的努力 训练和教诲
For what?
都是为了什么
To smile in the face of my brother's killer,
你让我强颜欢笑 面对我的仇人
while you make your own plans?
但你心里却另有打算
Alejandro, I taught you everything you need to survive.
阿利亚多 我教过你 你取胜所需要的一切
Now I must look to my own heart.
可我有自己的感情
Elena is all have left.
我只剩下伊莲娜了
I'm not going to lose her again.
不能再一次失去她
What about California?
可加利福尼亚怎么办
What about the people?
人民怎么办
They still have Zorro.
他们还有会罗
I've every inch of the countryside covered.
我已经控制了每一寸土地
If he shows himself...
如果他胆敢出现
are you all right?
你没事吧
Do you have the map?
那张地图呢
We'll find it.
我们会找到的
Is your army ready to fight Santa Anna's?
难道你准备跟山塔安纳开战吗
No, sir.
不 先生
Then why are you asking me if I'm all right?
那你还问我是不是有事
You know, I'm really beginning to wonder
我甚至
if you want this operation to succeed at all. Captain Love.
开始怀疑你是不是真想 完成这项计划勒福上尉
Just what are you saying, Don Rafael?
我不明白你在说什么
What I'm saying, Captain,
你听清楚了 我的意思是说.. .
is that I think that my horse could run this army better than you.
就连我的马 都比你更会管理军队
I said I'll find him.
我说过会找到佐罗
That means I will.
我说到做到
Perhaps I can save you the trouble.
我看你不用费事了
Go on, reach for it...Captain!
我知道你在掏枪 上尉
Who are you?
你是谁
I warned you long ago, Rafael...
很久以前我敬告过你 拉斐尔
you would never be rid of me.
你永远别想摆脱我
De la Vega.
德罗维加
Rafael.
拉斐尔
You were not the Zorro I saw last night.
你不是我昨晚见到的佐罗
That was your master, Don Alejandro.
佐罗是你的主人阿利亚多先生
Yes.
没错
But there are many who would proudly wear the mask of Zorro.
可是还有更多的人 想要带上佐罗的面具
Either way, it's of little consequence.
就算那样也无济于事
Events have been set in motion that you cannot stop.
事情已成定局 你无法阻止
I'm not here to stop you.
我不是来阻止你的
Call for Elena.
叫伊莲娜来
Call her.
岂她
Captain...
上和尉
bring my daughter to me.
去叫我女儿到这来
Bring her to me!
快点去
You cannot imagine, Rafael,
你无法想象 拉斐尔
how I have dreamed of this moment.
我做梦都在想着这一天
Night and day, twenty long years.
日复一日 整整20年了
Really?
是吗
[ haven't given you a second thought.
可我一次也没想过你
If l...die, De la Vega, the truth dies with me.
如果我死了 德罗维加 真相也就消失了
We shall see.
走着瞧吧
Father!
父亲
Bernardo, what are you doing?
伯纳德 你想干什么
Tell her, Rafael.
告诉她 拉斐尔
Tell me what? What is going on?
告诉什么 出什么事了
Tell her who her real father is.
告诉她 谁是她的亲生父亲
Father, what is he saying?
他在说什么
This...unfortunate man lost a daughter once...
这个不幸的人
and it has driven him mad.
他失去了女儿
And...now, he seeks to claim you for his own.
从此他就疯了 现在他要你当他的女儿
Tell her how her mother died.
告诉她 她母亲是怎么死的
Your daughter is lost, De la Vega.
你的女儿 她回不来了 德罗维加
You cannot have mine.
你得不到我女儿
De la Vega?
德罗维加
A woman in town, she told me.
城里有个女人曾经对我说
Diego De la Vega?
狄葛。德罗维加
Father?
父亲
His name is of no consequence.
他的名字一文不值
I was told my ninera used to hang something on my crib.
她说保姆经常在我的摇篮里 挂一些东西
Yes...she had her hang a...fresh...flower...
是的 你母亲让她挂心爱的鲜花
No!
不
Let us finish it, Rafael.
让我们做个了结吧
Let us finish what we started...
就从爱佩莎死的.… .
the night Esperanza died.
那天晚上开始
Drop your sword...
放下你的剑
or I will have no choice, but to have you shot.
否则我就只能打死你
Even in the presence of my daughter.
甚至当着我女儿的面
Please.
求你了
They were flowers.
那些鲜花
Romneya.
是马氏婴栗
Rafael...
拉斐尔
she knows.
她明白了
Water!
给他拿水
Lock them up!
把他们关起来
The fuses are burning. Hurry it up.
已经点火了 动作快点
Let's go.
出发
Wait here.
等着我
Secure the wagon. Stay alert.
保护好马车 严加防范
De la Vega.
德罗维加
Rafael.
拉斐尔
Only one question.
我只问你一个问题
Really?
是吗
What is that?
什么问题
How would you like your remains displayed?
你打算怎么处理你的尸体
Now I'm free...to kill you.
现在我可以要你的命了
No!
不
Drop the sword.
把剑放下
Drop it.
放下
You really think I would have killed my own child?
你真以为我会杀死自己的女儿
No!
不
Did you miss me?
在找我吗
Elena! Get them out!
伊茵娜 快去放人
"M"...for Murrieta.
Il 指我的兄弟
Two men.
你我
One death!
必有一死
You're doin’ well.
你干得不错
Your brother would have shot himself by now.
要是你哥哥 早就完了
Alejandro.
阿利亚多
ls it finished?
都结束了
Yes, Don Diego...it's finished.
是的 狄葛 都结束了
Not for Zorro.
除了佐罗
There will be other days, other battles to fight.
也许有一天还需要他战斗
It is your curse and destiny.
那是你的的言和使命
My beautiful Elena.
我美丽的伊莲娜
The world is a strange place.
这个世界真是很奇怪
To have found you at last, only to lose you again.
我终于找到了你 可又要失去你了
You will never lose me...
你永远不会失去我
Father.
我的父亲
Elena...
伊莲娜
you are like your mother.
你长得像你母亲
Same eyes.
同样的眼睛
Same mouth.
同样的嘴巴
Same spirit.
同样的心灵
Alejandro...
阿利亚多
Elena.
伊莲娜
And so it was.
故事就是这样
Lightning split the sky...
闪电划破长空
thunder shook the Earth.
圳雳震憾大地
Then, all was quiet.
随后一切归于平静
The great warrior known as...
一个伟大的战士
Zotro...was gone.
佐罗 离去了
People of the land gave him a hero's funeral,
这块土地上的人民 为他举行了英雄的苗礼
the largest anyone had ever seen.
盛况是那样空前
They came from far and wide
他们从四面八方赶来
to say farewell to the brave and noble champion.
向这位杰出勇敢的战士 做最后道别
But don't worry, little Joaquin.
不过别担心 小沃金
Whenever great deeds are remembered...
你祖父的英雄事迹
your grandfather will live on.
将永远活在人民的心中
For there must always, always be a Zorro.
佐罗是永远 永远不会消失的
And someday, when he's needed, we will see him again.
每当人们需要他的时候 他就会再度出现
On his fearsome steed, Tornado, riding like the wind,
骑着他那匹黑色的骏马 风驰电气
his sword blazing in the sun.
宝剑在阳光下 闪闪发光
Leaping...
奔腾
. . jumping...
跳跃
swinging through the air.
来去无踪
Fighting like a lion, fighting like a tiger, fighting...
像一头雄狮 像一头猛虎 战斗 战斗
as safely as possible.
可是他永远不会出事的
Is this your idea of putting the baby to sleep?
你就是这样哄孩子入睡的吗
Sleep tight, my son.
隆吧 我的儿子
When I sleep I will dream of this...
我的睡梦中常常会出现
dashing rogue, Zorro.
一个勇敢的身影 佐罗
But what face shall I give him?
可他到底长得什么样子
He has been many different men, but...
佐罗是许许多多不同的人
he has loved you as all of them.
可无论是谁都会爱上你
How can I refuse such a man?
这样的人我怎么能拒绝呢
Do you know where I might find him?
你知道在哪能找到他
You know Zorro...
你很熟悉佐罗
he could be anywhere.
他无处不在
There, there, my darling.
隆吧 宝贝